experteer.co.uk 2009-03-18

# Experteer - Data protection.

Experteer GmbH respects your right to privacy. This Privacy Policy sets out details of the information that we may collect from you and how we may use that information. Except where otherwise stated, defined terms used in this Privacy Policy shall have the same meaning as the terms defined in the Terms. Please read this Privacy Policy carefully - by using this Website and the Website Services you agree to the provisions of this Privacy Policy (as amended from time to time).

If, for any reason, you do not agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy, please stop using the Website immediately.

### Who are we?

In this Privacy Policy, references to "we" or "us" are to Experteer GmbH which is the data controller of personal data collected from you on the Website. Experteer GmbH acts through its branch in the United Kingdom, whose registered number is BR009789 and whose registered office is at 8-14 Crinan Street, London N1 8JQ.

If you have any questions about how we collect, store and use your information, you may contact us by telephoning +49 (0)89 - 55 27 93 - 150 or by e-mailing us at [info@experteer.co.uk](mailto:info@experteer.co.uk).

### Brief legal background

We will at all times only collect and process your personal information in accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998, the Privacy and Electronic Communications (EC Directive) Regulations 2003 and any other applicable data protection legislation.

### What information do we collect and how do we collect it?

When you apply for and use the Website or the Website Services or contact us by post, telephone, fax, e-mail or SMS, we may collect, store and use certain personal information that you disclose to us to process your application and make available the relevant Website Service, and (where you have consented) in relation to certain marketing activities.

The information that we may collect from you includes your name, address, telephone, fax, e-mail and mobile contact details, your User Generated Content (which will include your CV), details of the Website Services that you use through the Website and information that we collect as you interact with the Website and your credit or debit card details. We may also collect details of your computer's internet protocol address, which is automatically collected by our web server. Finally, we may receive information about you from third parties (such as credit reference agencies) who are legally entitled to disclose that information.

In addition we may collect anonymous information about your use of the Website using cookies, pixel tags and similar functionality.

### How do we use your information?

By using the Website and/or the Website Services, you agree that your information may be used by us for any of the following purposes: (a) to process membership applications and to service your membership (including maintaining membership and user records); (b) to provide you with a personalised browsing experience when using the Website and to improve the functionality of the Website; (c) to provide the relevant Website Service (including informing you about job advertisements from carefully screened third parties (such as recruiters and headhunters)) and fulfil any contractual agreements between you and us (for example, when you apply for a job by clicking on a link on the Website); (d) as part of the Website Services to send you details (including by post, phone, fax, e-mail or SMS) of current topics in the labour and recruitment markets and news concerning us; (e) to send you details of our services and/or other similar products and services which we think may interest you, unless you inform us in writing that you do not want to receive these details; (f) to manage any account that you hold with us; and (g) to comply with legal and regulatory requirements.

**If you do not want to receive marketing communications from us please e-mail[info@experteer.co.uk](mailto:info@experteer.co.uk).**

We **never** rent or sell your information to third parties. We do occasionally reveal information to third parties about the use of the Website but this information does not contain personal data.

We use third parties to process payment for Membership. All payment transaction information is processed using secure socket layer (SSL) technology or technology offering a similar or better level of security.

We do store and process information that we collect about you within the European Economic Area, in particular at Experteer GmbH in Germany and at other Experteer locations. Third parties such as recruiters or headhunters may access our data base from locations outside the European Economic Area and in doing so may store or process information that we collect about you outside the European Economic Area in locations which may have lower standards of data protection. We may also disclose your information to third parties in connection with the sale, transfer or disposal of our business (and/or any preparatory steps in connection with the same), provided that they continue to use your information substantially in accordance with the terms of this Privacy Policy.

We have put in place technical and organisational security measures which seek to prevent the loss or unauthorised access of your personal information. However, whilst we have used all reasonable efforts to ensure the security of your data, please be aware that we cannot guarantee the security of information transmitted over the Internet.

### Your Profile and Contacting You

You have access and control over your profile by using the profile editing tools available on the Website when logged into your account. The profile information that you submit to us will not be visible to third party users of the Website such as headhunters and recruiters until you have completed your profile. Employers are not permitted to have access to your profile at any time. You can determine at any time which groups of persons can see your profile and whether it is displayed in full, anonymously or not at all. If you choose to be visible to third parties (whether anonymously or not), as part of our Website Services, we allow them to request contact with you by sending a message through us to inform you of job opportunities. When you receive such a message you can then elect whether you wish that third party to contact you directly. You understand that personal data such as your CV will be visible to these perons (although, unless you separately agree, they may only use this data to send a message to you through us).

If you do not want to receive e-mail or other communications directly from us and/or third parties (including headhunters), you should not consent to uses of your personal information that allow such communications. However, if you do not consent to receive marketing communications then you could miss out on receiving important information on new job opportunities and other offers from us and from our third party partners. **You can choose not to receive any more marketing communications by e-mailing us at[info@experteer.co.uk](mailto:info@experteer.co.uk) at any time.**

It is important to us that all employers, recruiters and headhunters who use the Website are legitimately seeking applicants and we operate a strict screening procedure. We do not allow employers to contact you directly at all and we only allow recruiters or headhunters to contact you directly through your account on the Website where you agree to be visible to such parties. Your privacy is important to us and if you become aware of a third party misusing your information then please inform us immediately and we will try to assist you in protecting the privacy of your information.

### What are your rights?

Your rights include the right to contact us in order to find out what information we hold about you (please note that a £10 fee will be payable) or to access, cancel or correct any information that we hold about you. Please consult the Information Commissioner's website for further details of your data protection rights ([www.ico.gov.uk](http://www.ico.gov.uk/)).

You may also contact us in writing to inform us if you do not wish to receive any marketing materials from us or from third party partners.

### What are cookies?

The Website uses cookies. Cookies are small files stored on your computer's hard drive which are used to collect your personal information. You may choose to refuse cookies but, if you do so, some of the functionality of the Website may not longer be available to you. If you access the Website via one of our partner sites then we will not save any personal information but the anonymised data will be saved in a cookie so that we can maintain the partner programme. These cookies are automatically deleted on registration or (if you do not register) 30 days after you access the site.

For more information about cookies, including further details as to what they are and how to refuse them, please visit [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

### Links

This Website contains links to other websites. We are not responsible for the privacy practices of other websites. When you use a link on our site you must read the privacy statement(s) of the relevant third party site to which you are transferred. This Privacy Policy applies solely to information collected by us. We are not responsible for, and have no control over, information that you send to third party websites or that they collect independently of the Website (please also see Clause 10 of our Terms).

### How up-to-date is this Privacy Policy?

We may update or amend this Privacy Policy from time to time to comply with law or to meet our changing business requirements without notice to you. Any updates or amendments will be posted on the Website. By continuing to use the Website or by continued use of our Website Services, you agree to be bound by the terms of these updates and amendments.

This Privacy Policy was last updated in January 2008.
